G Manikam

Raipur, Chhattisgarh gmanikam2_f4v@indeedemail.com +91 62613 11200

Objective

To be a part of highly motivated team and make the best use of my potential and skills to rise our organization up to the pinnacle of success and gradually make my way with my experience to become successful entrepreneur.

Working

Having 6+ years of experience in Web Application Development, (MERN Stack, Full stack developer) with a demonstrated history of

working in the information technology and service industry. Skilled ReactJS, MongoDB, ExpressJS, Node JS, Laravel, Github and Gitlab.

And I am working as a Senior Team Lead in Focus Media since 2022 and still working here.

Work Experience

Senior Team Lead

Focus Media - Raipur, Chhattisgarh September 2022 to Present

I am working here as a senior team lead.

Responsibility-

- Managed development milestones from initial steps through final delivery.
- Gathered and defined customer requirements to develop clear specifications for project plans.
- Built, tested and deployed scalable, highly available and modular software products.
- Maintained existing applications and designed and delivered new applications.

Senior Software Programmer, (Full stack developer)

Nyusoft Solutions - Ahmedabad, Gujarat

May 2021 to August 2022

I am working here as a senior software programmer. And i have 3 projects in which i handle one project and leads it with juniors and remaining in two projects working with team.

- Contributed ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs and enhancements.
- Managed development milestones from initial steps through final delivery.
- Gathered and defined customer requirements to develop clear specifications for project plans.
- Built, tested and deployed scalable, highly available and modular software products.
- Maintained existing applications and designed and delivered new applications.

Full Stack Developer

WebMi Digital Solutions

- Designed and developed efficient and maintainable software according to business objectives and needs of various clients.
- Managed development milestones from initial steps through final delivery.
- Consulted with engineering team members to determine system loads and develop improvement plans.
- Took initial concepts and developed project plans.
- Contributed ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs and enhancements.
- Delivered performance-driven and user-centric websites that met all business requirements.
- Orchestrated efficient large-scale software deployments, including testing features and correcting code.
- Gathered and defined customer requirements to develop clear specifications for project plans.
- Built, tested and deployed scalable, highly available and modular software products.
- Maintained existing applications and designed and delivered new applications.
- Built databases and table structures for web applications.

Web Developer (Full stack developer)

Consta Cloud 2019 to 2020

- Provided front-end website development using Node Js, Express Js, MongoDB, Twig.
- Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence with Twig, JavaScript, AJAX coding.
- Oversaw back-end development using Node Is to maintain website integrity, security and efficiency.
- Multi-tasked across multiple functions and roles to generate project results and meet deadlines and organizational expectations.
- Implemented website maintenance, content management, update and security resource tutorials to assist end-user training.
- Coded websites using Node JS Twig HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery languages.

Web Developer, (Full stack developer)

NB Digital Technology 2016 to 2019

- Provided front-end website development using Laravel, Php, React Js.
- Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence with HTML, JavaScript, AJAX coding.
- Oversaw back-end development using PHP to maintain website integrity, security and efficiency.
- Employed coding practices based on commonly accepted standards to establish site layout and user interface.
- Multi-tasked across multiple functions and roles to generate project results and meet deadlines and organizational expectations.
- Built and styled mobile-friendly websites, transitioning legacy presentations to simultaneous mobile-friendly versions.
- Conducted testing and review of website design for responsiveness, clarity and effectiveness.
- Pulled from PHP, SQL, JavaScript and other back-end library knowledge to bolster programming resources.
- Coded websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery languages.
- Giving Training to interns on React Js, And Laravel.

Education

MCA in SSGI, Bhilai

Board /University 2016

BCA

Pt. HarishankarShukla College 2013

Skills / IT Skills

- React JS
- Node Js
- Express Js
- MongoDB
- Laravel
- Php
- Ajax
- MySql
- HTML5
- JavaScript